# Mário Antônio A. Rodeghiero

#### FRONT END · DEVELOPER

88034-102, Rod. Amaro Antônio Vieira 2259 Apt. 404, Florianópolis - SC, Brazil

□ (+55) 99691-2866 | 🗷 mario.rodeghiero@gmail.com | 🏕 www.mariorodeghiero.com | 🖸 mariorodeghiero | 🛅 mariorodeghiero

## Summary\_

After a solid career of 10 years in the telecommunications area, I decided that after the birth of my son, it would be time to change the area and look for new challenges. Since June 2017, I dedicate my free time to study development, contribute to Open Source projects and improve my English, in the future (beginning of 2019) seek an opportunity as a developer. Graduate student in Data science and Big Data Analytics and in parallel I continue my studies focused on Front End, I have as main programming language "Javascript" but I also have knowledge of Python. I keep my personal codes and projects on Github and I have also developed my blog to put my learning into practice by publishing articles on development. I am also the creator of "Vue Theme", theme with more than 26000 Installs in the Visual Studio Code editor.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Claro S/A Florianópolis - Brazil

DATACENTER ANALYST II

Apr 2013 - Jun 2017

• Responsible for implementing and managing the Datacenter infrastructure, installing, configuring, monitoring and performing preventive and corrective maintenance on large equipment in high-availability environments and mission critical as servers (Oracle Solaris) DHCP, DNS, TFTP, LDAP, routers (Cisco and Huawei), Switches (Cisco) and CMTS (Cisco, Arris, House System and Motorola), responsible for the generation and distribution of DOCSIS technology services (broadband Internet, VOIP and video On Demand) through the HFC network, for more than 170,000 customers in the cities of Florianópolis, São José and Palhoça. Main activities also include the management of LAN and WAN networks (IPv4, IPv6, and NAT) routing, BGP, IS-IS and OSPF, and traffic Balancing control, administration of links, monitoring, troubleshooting and network documentation, assist in developing and maintaining internal systems, through markup languages, programming and database, such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and level 2 support to the operations of course Brazil (Net, Embratel) throughout the State of Santa Catarina, helping, guiding and planning demands for Datacenter teams to the cities of Balneário Camboriú, Blumenau, Brusque, Chapecó, Criciúma, Itajaí, Itapema, Joinville and Navegantes.

Claro S/A Florianópolis - Brazil

TECHNICIAN III

Aug 2012 to Apr 2013

I worked on the identification and resolution of problems in the external coaxial network aiming at the maintenance of signal quality. It carried
out preventive network alignment works, aiming at reducing complaints and signal degradation and collaborating for the quality of the network
system by supporting the other technical areas by solving fiber disruptions and incidents in the HFC network, in order to reach the stipulated
goals for the company.

NET S/A Florianópolis - Brazil

TECHNICIAN II

Jun 2010 - Jul 2012

• I worked with support and customer service, making DOCSIS 2.0 and 3.0 technology configurations, Digital Technology, and access point. I performed maintenance in Fixed Telephony Network, Indoor RF Network, Preventive in Indor Amplifiers, contributing directly to customer satisfaction

#### **RCtel Solution in Telecommunications**

Florianópolis - Brazil

SUPPORT ANALYST

Aug 2008 - May 2010

• I worked on Backbone configuration for long distance radio using 2.4GHz and 5GHz technology equipment. It also provided remote customer service and support, running network troubleshooting to identify and resolve issue

#### **Education**

### University Estácio de Sá

Florianópolis, Brazil

GRADUATE STUDIES DATA SCIENCE AND BIG DATA ANALYTICS

Dec. 2018 - PRESENT

#### University Estácio de Sá

Florianópolis, Brazil

TECHNICIAN'S LICENSE COMPUTER NETWORKS

Dec. 2016

## Technical skills

React.js, Javascript (ES5 e ES6), Python, HTML, CSS, SASS (Preprocessor), styled-components, ElectronJS, Css Frameworks(Bootstrap, Bulma), Git e Github, Webpack, Gulp, Programming logic.

## Languages\_

Portuguese, English

2